Hello people, welcome to our class today.
We have news here as we are going to record the Seu Elias Kids Collection.
It is a children's collection. They are some models that we are going to do with modern hairs in children.
Remembering that we are launching the Seu Elias Kids this week at the barbershop, which will be a collaboration
both among the barbershop and with the Barber Day Online. Hope you like it.
It will be a little more summarized class with the aim of creating new things and I hope you like it a lot.
Come on.
Cutting children's hair has some peculiarities. In our model's hair, which is Luis, he already
is not so young as he is developing in a teenager. So, the particularities are no longer
so big. In children's hair I always say that we have to do it fast.
Since he starts scratching, to be impatient, the mother begins to be impatient too and that causes
discomfort for both the child and the professional. And it ends up being a not very good job.
We are going to cut in a easier way, I do not use division and I do not make so much cut in
child's hair to save time and make it a good job but considering the time.
In Luis's hair we will make a lateral gradient and we will also make a crop up and leave
the bangs a little shorter forward so that it stays a square but also
summed up to take time into account.
I will always start the gradient with comb one. In the same way I do not divide in this case.
In children's hair like Luis I avoid working hard with a razor, shaver, leaving a lot of scraping.
We do it more, in the case of having to scrape a lot, with a machine at 0 to not cause
an impact as aggressive as we would on an adult.
We use comb 1, both on one side and the other, with very modern hair marking the side
that suits Luis's face a lot and the style we want to do.
Behind the ear I go a finger size with comb 1 or 2, according to your criteria.
Another important tip is, not only in children's hairs, when you are going to make movements and pass the comb 1 or 2,
go in a short way to avoid having to go back to the same area and become repetitive
to the point of tiring your model or client.
It is always important to constantly clean the client so that he is not scratching or uncomfortable.
Following our criteria we will go with comb 1 in this darker area and this
procedure does not differ much from adult hair.
I always talk about the topic of agility in the barbershop because children get impatient, hair starts
to fall into their eyes or ears, the child begins to move and be restless which ends up hindering the quality.
The more agile you can be the better.
We will work with the 1.5 comb above this line that we are doing here.
You can see that I have not done that horse shoe division but I have in my mind the imaginary line
to keep the crown and the edge. The line is not there but it is always in my mind.
After comb 1.5 we return to comb 1. Removing this short shadow that we have here from comb 1 to 2.
It is always important that the hand is light to not make marks on the child's skin as it has
the skin much more sensitive than an adult so you have to be careful.
After moving from comb 1 to comb 2, we will now move on to comb 0.5.
Remembering that we are not going to pass a razor to the point of finishing it as an adult, just to make it a little clearer.
We're going through the process of creating this lightweight mark that you already know from the other videos. Following the same rule
than in the other hairs. I don't usually change my court base or the way to do it, or just because it's an adult or a child,
the concept will always be the same. Follow a normal gradient procedure, like all others.
There will be people saying, "I wish the child was still like Luis." The truth is that cutting children's hair is not easy.
But I think it's a good conversation, to talk to them as an equal. In the case of the barbershop we are putting
video games, strollers for younger children... I think that all that makes it much easier.
After taking the comb 0.5 we will go to comb 0 low. We will follow the whole procedure
like the others, however, now we are going to get all the hair down here.
I will not do it only in the middle of the head.
Always be very careful so that the machine does not pinch behind the ear.
I am making the mark and taking out the mark for those clients in which I do not want to use the razor I always do so.
I really believe that in all barbershops what they do the most are degraded, and I don't use the razor since
not all customers like the razor...
So, in the day to day, in the barbershop, that's how we do it.
Of course, we have clients where we scrape, but in other clients we prefer not to scrape so much.
Remember to always be cleaning. Is very important, especially when it comes to children.
Otherwise, they begin to lose patience and be restless.
The next step is to wet the hair. I told you earlier that I am going to make a crop but I have doubts since his hair
is very pretty. Maybe I do something modern-cut or something.
Although in a hair like Luis I will not do much cutting or division, I need to make a lock as a guide
to make everything the same size. Before making that lock, I work with Babum's grooming,
As you know, they will help me both to finish the hairstyle and to divide. We wet it a lot.
Since I want to work my hair in a very good way and we are going to take some pictures,
I will not get much hair since I want to have a little length in this hair.
Continuing we will make a central section in the same way.
It is always important to make that clean separation to move the center line.
I will start from the center. And since I want to leave the upper part, I will start at the front.
I'm going to leave my comb and I'm going to cut that straight strand.
My hand will always be diagonal to leave that upper part bigger.
Here too. And here too. It is only to define the size of the entire hair.
After having defined it we can make the famous, lock by lock.
And what is lock by lock? I will distribute that central hair lock inside the hair and I will take
sections in the horizontal, put it up and find my guiding lock of hair.
Look at it here in the center. Then, I cut straight based on my guide.
Here she is again. See here again. And we make a normal lock to lock.
We must always have a guiding lock of hair to not make random strands.
In the next section we will take the same way but with my hand at 90 degrees.
I can't rest my hand since I want Luis's hair to stay more square.
There is very little hair on the sides. Can you see it? Where more hair has gone so far has been in the center.
We carry all the sections for the horizontal and to align this hair, if I have cut all the sections
in the horizontal, let's do it now in the vertical.
I take it in the same way leaving the toupee always bigger. Always taking very little and keeping a straight hand.
Remembering an adult cut with a child cut, the more the child cut is similar to the adult cut the better.
In this case here, Luis has a more teenager face and that is the concept that
we will explore in the collection photos too.
We are not going to make the models wear a Captain America or Power Rangers shirt; we are going to put a
more classic style with blazer and glasses to make them look more adult.
I think it's a very good concept and I have the whole collection in my mind now.
Well, to connect this hair and pull this mark, I'm going to take it out almost all and I'm going to leave it a little darker.
We make a diagonal division backwards, taking here from the usual side as we always do.
However, I am going to connect also here in a more practical way which is as if we were making a lock by lock.
See. You have to remember whenever my hand can't be lying down, it always has to be
straight so you can make his hair more square shaped.
If you prefer to grab it as I am doing here, there is no problem. On the contrary, you can grab it this way too.
You hold it, leave the comb and cut straight.
Generally, when they are children, I like to hold it in a more practical way to be a little faster
since children don't let it take a long time. There is no need and children, sometimes, will not help much being still.
We go here again. We separate from side. Then, I put a finger on the root.
Now I'm going to start taking a bit of this slope. Scissor and comb.
I will only throw away the excess of this shadow and it is very important that I clean the hairs of the client's eyes.
Be very careful not to reduce much in the edges area.
Slide comb. It is very important to do the comb job very well. Today students come to me and we have a subject
totally dedicated to the comb and we work with mannequins.
We know if they have a good grip on the scissors, they know how to make divisions but at the time of doing the sliding comb
it is a common difficulty. Almost everyone who comes has a lot of difficulty.
So, the sliding of the comb has some peculiarities that if they are not really respected
you can't have a good comb slide.
Always work the thumb and the blades always aligned with each other, both the bottom and top.
Having done that, we now go with the scissors to remove some of this shadow.
I have already spoken several times about the scissors and the ideal is to always cut with the teeth on the top.
We are removing the excesses but not taking everything out to leave a little shadow on the sides
without it being too strong or too dark.
People, now up here we can do a checking with the jagged scissors as I am going to do now.
What am I going to do now? I will take sections in the horizontal, I will place a finger at the root and
I'm going to give two or three jaws near the tips.
Just to leave the hair a little more disconnected and light.
I am not doing this to drain too much the hair but with wisdom not to detonate much the hair,
moreover, to not detonate anything.
We are going to go to a more creative part where I am going to style his hair a little. In the front, here,
I'm going to get some hair with the 1.5 comb just so it stays a little more stylized and not so traditional and formal.
Just to give it a more European look and we're going to style a little here making a small line or something.
Do you like the beard?
Yes I like.
Do you? You don't have any yet.
My father has a big beard.
He has? And you're going to have a beard too, boy.
Let's dry it a little to see how the hair is looking.
You can see that although the hair has been done with a little more agility, without so much division,
the basic requirements are always respected. They cannot be forgotten.
The edges, crowns, this more ascending frontal part... is it very important.
We are going to do a little detail here in the front, to level a bit as we usually do so.
And it will be a stylistic detail that will be better for photos.
I always like to do a cleaning with the razor, as I did before, because it always stays clearer and cleaner.
We are going to correct in this frontal part. Now we are cleaning the front to remove only the excess,
gently not to hurt the skin.
This frontal alignment is very important that it is straight and even but always remembering that perfect does not exist.
It is always important to keep an eye on the mirror, take a walk...
I really like to scrape against hair growth so it takes a little longer to grow.
I have doubts in matching and correcting here but I am not going to do it, I prefer to leave it as it is eye-catching as well.
The conventional thing is to make a square but I like to leave it a little more different than the rest of the market.
I use the pencil to leave it a little bigger and on the side. I use pencil in both the photos and the video, however,
in the day to day we do not use it. In the production it is very important to have makeup and a complement for these parts
that are clearer and inaccurate. I think the pencil colors these edges a little more.
People, I'm going to make a little detail in his hair. Today for social networks or photos, just cut
the hair does not attract much attention, you will always need a little detail or an extra.
In this case, I think it will be very good to make a small simple detail but that will attract attention.
Now we take the razor to do only in the shaved area. I usually wet it with a bit of water to not put an excess of saving cream.
Now with comb 1 to remove only that excess of the gradient which will make it a little more marked.
This line is very traditional and we do it a lot of adults hair. As I told you before
the proposal is not to make a child's hair but an adult hair in children.
So, both the look and the hair have to be inspired and with a more adult touch.
Let's texturize a little up here scissoring with the tip of the scissors.
So that the hair stays a little looser.
To finish our model hairstyle I will use only a little brush here.
And finally, to end the client's hair, I'm going to use Babum's ointment powder.
Why do I like this Babum ointment powder? Because it will give me volume and I need it to work well
the final touches and stylization of the hair. I want volume.
And then I will also work with Babum's matt ointment. We put a not very large amount and
we go through the entire hair. Let's stylize it in general.
Even in child's hair we respect all the requirements such as leaving it squared shape, respecting the crown, the edge...
Now we are going to use the Babum spray to fix the hair well.
A very important detail in the completion not only of a child's hair but in any hair,
it is always important that the client leaves clean.
People, he have already finished the our model's hair, Luis. It's a hair with a more adult style with a big toupee,
I have made that line more curved and concave, the front alignment, I have preserved the edges, the normal upward toupee,
crown preserved... Its gradient has not been so bold because it is possible that the mother could not be
so satisfied and, in children's hair, it is important to always be careful with.
I hope you liked it, see you in the next video. See you soon!